<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WiFi on Debashish Sahu</title>
    <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/tags/wifi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WiFi on Debashish Sahu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.debashishsahu.com/tags/wifi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sending sensor data from ESP32 to InfluxDB | Local access - time-series database</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/sending-sensor-data-from-esp32-to-influxdb-local-access-time-series-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/sending-sensor-data-from-esp32-to-influxdb-local-access-time-series-database/</guid>
      <description>Instead of sending data to services in the cloud, here we send sensor data to local InfluxDB database. Grafana is used to read data from InfluxDB and alert thresholds are set to send reactive alerts.
InfluxDB Download and Installation: official docs
Docker Download and Installation: official docs
ESP32 connecting to WPA2-Enterprise   Hardware  ESP32 TTGo T-Energy SSD1306 OLED display BME280 sensor  Software Dependencies Listed below are the dpendencies used by Arduino IDE, but use PlatformIO instead!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect ESP32 to WPA2-Enterprise WiFi (eduroam: University of Michigan Wireless)</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/connect-esp32-to-wpa2-enterprise-wifi-eduroam-university-of-michigan-wireless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/connect-esp32-to-wpa2-enterprise-wifi-eduroam-university-of-michigan-wireless/</guid>
      <description>Walkthrough of minimal settings for ESP32 to connect to WPA2-Enterprise WiFi at University of Michigan (eduroam)
GitHub: debsahu/Esp32_EduWiFi Minimal settings for ESP32 to connect to University of Michigan WiFi (MWireless/eduroam)
 MSetup   Go to MSetup
  Log in using University of Michigan credentials
  Select Other Device and log in again if needed
  Enter Device Name, MAC Address, uniqname will already be selected, Advanced Options &amp;gt; Network Type &amp;gt; Internet Access After above settings are enterd, click on Register my device</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESPHome Dot Matrix Display | Internet Connected Display Home Assistant Display</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/esphome-dot-matrix-display-internet-connected-display-home-assistant-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/esphome-dot-matrix-display-internet-connected-display-home-assistant-display/</guid>
      <description>    Using ESPHome for connecting ESP8266 to MAX7219 Dot-Matrix Display to show useful information from Home Assistant. This is used by my wife&amp;rsquo;s channel Canvasyvibes Art
Software: ESPHome  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voice Controlled (Connected) BIDET: A Solution for Non-Availability of Toilet-Paper Caused by COVID19</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/voice-controlled-connected-bidet-a-solution-for-non-availability-of-toilet-paper-caused-by-covid19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/voice-controlled-connected-bidet-a-solution-for-non-availability-of-toilet-paper-caused-by-covid19/</guid>
      <description>    Install of Biobidet Bliss BB200 and connecting it to Home-Assistant.
Wilbur Sargunaraj   Software: ESPHome  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESP32 to Process Audio Signals: Software (Fourier Transforms) and Hardware (MSGEQ7)</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/esp32-to-process-audio-signals-software-fourier-transforms-and-hardware-msgeq7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/esp32-to-process-audio-signals-software-fourier-transforms-and-hardware-msgeq7/</guid>
      <description>Here we use ESP32 microcontroller to analyze real-time audio signals
 Real-time FFT to get frequencies Use MSGEQ7 chip to get the same data Display frequency bands on LEDs as bars  FFT basics:   GitHub: debsahu/ESP32_FFT_Audio_LEDs Libraries Needed Software FFT platformio.ini and Hardware FFT platformio.ini is included, use PlatformIO and it will take care of installing the following libraries.
   Library Link     arduinoFFT https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESP8266/ESP3232: Home Assistant Switch Connected to PCF8574 Controlling 8 AC Relays</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/esp8266-esp3232-home-assistant-switch-connected-to-pcf8574-controlling-8-ac-relays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/esp8266-esp3232-home-assistant-switch-connected-to-pcf8574-controlling-8-ac-relays/</guid>
      <description>Home Assistant Switch for 8 Relays: PCF8574 can be used to extend the GPIO of ESP8266/32 and here we use 8 ports of PCF8574 to control 8 Relay module
GitHub: debsahu/PCF8574_8Relay Home Assistant Switch for 8 Relays
 Code can compile on ESP8266/32 PCF8574 can be used to extend the GPIO of ESP8266/32 8 ports of PCF8574 is connected to 8 Relay module  Libraries Needed platformio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Button: Amazon &#34;Dash&#34; Type Button to Communicate to Home-Assistant</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/the-button-amazon-dash-type-button-to-communicate-to-home-assistant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/the-button-amazon-dash-type-button-to-communicate-to-home-assistant/</guid>
      <description>An attempt to build a Amazon &amp;ldquo;Dash&amp;rdquo; type button to communicate with Home Assistant, which is a combination of two different projects
GitHub: debsahu/TheButton Things we want to achieve:  Low on power consumtion: ESP8266 is OFF when the button is not pressed debsahu/ESP_External_Interrupt Portable: Uses 18650 battery, lasts years Talks to Home Assistant: debsahu/HARestAPI    ESP_External_Interrupt  GitHub: https://github.com/debsahu/ESP_External_Interrupt
  HARestAPI  GitHub: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Twitter Using TwitterWebAPI for ESP8266</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/talking-to-twitter-using-twitterwebapi-for-esp8266/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/talking-to-twitter-using-twitterwebapi-for-esp8266/</guid>
      <description>Idea:  Use ESP8266 to talk to Twitter Get User Data or Tweet or Search Twitter Display the data on a Dot-Matrix display  Implementation I created an Arduino library to talk to Twitter using its Web API made for ESP8266. There are other approaches like using a bearer token arduino-twitter-api, but comes with limitations in terms of not being able to send tweet. This Arduino library TwitterWebAPI can both search/read and post tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet Connected Smoke Alarm</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/internet-connected-smoke-alarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/internet-connected-smoke-alarm/</guid>
      <description>Have you wondered how to build a internet connected smoke alarm using ESP8266 and a cheap Kidde RF-SM-DC?
Overall idea is to detect smoke alarm signals and send MQTT message. Home Assistant reads the MQTT message and sends out notifications that can be used to notify your local fire station.
ESP8266 sends a MQTT message until the smoke alarm is beeping.
Software Refer to https://github.com/debsahu/ESP_External_Interrupt to build the ESP8266 part of the internet connected smoke alarm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme Power-Save Mode: ESP8266 Powered ON After External Interrupt</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/extreme-power-save-mode-esp8266-powered-on-after-external-interrupt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/extreme-power-save-mode-esp8266-powered-on-after-external-interrupt/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how to turn on ESP8266 using external interrupt? Build a battery powered amazon dash button or a 18650 lipo powered door bell using ESP8266 without putting the device in deep sleep? Here is your answer.
Idea  Keep ESP8266 on OFF mode as default External 3.3V signal (can be short or long) arrives and turns ON ESP8266 ESP8266 wakes up and keeps itself awake until a task is perfomed Send MQTT data to server Put ESP8266 back to power OFF state  Implementation  RST pin is always HIGH/3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Dot Matrix Display: Twitter Mentions Using ESP8266 Adafruit.io and IFTTT</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/iot-dot-matrix-display-twitter-mentions-using-esp8266-adafruit-io-and-ifttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/iot-dot-matrix-display-twitter-mentions-using-esp8266-adafruit-io-and-ifttt/</guid>
      <description>Let’s say that you don’t have your smartphone around and someone mentions you on twitter. Wouldn’t it be nice to have a display that automatically reads your twitter mentions and show it on a scrolling display? So let’s build a internet controlled (IoT) dot-matrix display that does this for us using an ESP8266.
The plan to accomplish this is as follows:  Someone mentions us on twitter (in my case @debsahu) IF This Then That (IFTTT) tracks these mentions and posts this data on Adafruit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
