<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WPA2-Enterprise on Debashish Sahu</title>
    <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/tags/wpa2-enterprise/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WPA2-Enterprise on Debashish Sahu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.debashishsahu.com/tags/wpa2-enterprise/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sending sensor data from ESP32 to InfluxDB | Local access - time-series database</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/sending-sensor-data-from-esp32-to-influxdb-local-access-time-series-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/sending-sensor-data-from-esp32-to-influxdb-local-access-time-series-database/</guid>
      <description>Instead of sending data to services in the cloud, here we send sensor data to local InfluxDB database. Grafana is used to read data from InfluxDB and alert thresholds are set to send reactive alerts.
InfluxDB Download and Installation: official docs
Docker Download and Installation: official docs
ESP32 connecting to WPA2-Enterprise   Hardware  ESP32 TTGo T-Energy SSD1306 OLED display BME280 sensor  Software Dependencies Listed below are the dpendencies used by Arduino IDE, but use PlatformIO instead!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect ESP32 to WPA2-Enterprise WiFi (eduroam: University of Michigan Wireless)</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/connect-esp32-to-wpa2-enterprise-wifi-eduroam-university-of-michigan-wireless/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/connect-esp32-to-wpa2-enterprise-wifi-eduroam-university-of-michigan-wireless/</guid>
      <description>Walkthrough of minimal settings for ESP32 to connect to WPA2-Enterprise WiFi at University of Michigan (eduroam)
GitHub: debsahu/Esp32_EduWiFi Minimal settings for ESP32 to connect to University of Michigan WiFi (MWireless/eduroam)
 MSetup   Go to MSetup
  Log in using University of Michigan credentials
  Select Other Device and log in again if needed
  Enter Device Name, MAC Address, uniqname will already be selected, Advanced Options &amp;gt; Network Type &amp;gt; Internet Access After above settings are enterd, click on Register my device</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
