<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rtl-sdr on Debashish Sahu</title>
    <link>https://debsahu.github.io/tags/rtl-sdr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rtl-sdr on Debashish Sahu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://debsahu.github.io/tags/rtl-sdr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Image Recognition Using Movidius Neural Compute Stick on a RPi0W</title>
      <link>https://debsahu.github.io/posts/image-recognition-using-movidius-neural-compute-stick-on-a-rpi0w/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debsahu.github.io/posts/image-recognition-using-movidius-neural-compute-stick-on-a-rpi0w/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s build a security camera using Raspberry Pi Zero W and Movidius Neural Compute Stick to recognize a &amp;ldquo;person&amp;rdquo; on the video stream
GitHub: debsahu/PiCamMovidius Set up NCSDK API  Install required packages on Pi  sudo apt-get install -y libusb-1.0-0-dev libprotobuf-dev libleveldb-dev libsnappy-dev libopencv-dev libhdf5-serial-dev protobuf-compiler libatlas-base-dev git automake byacc lsb-release cmake libgflags-dev libgoogle-glog-dev liblmdb-dev swig3.0 graphviz libxslt-dev libxml2-dev gfortran python3-dev python-pip python3-pip python3-setuptools python3-markdown python3-pillow python3-yaml python3-pygraphviz python3-h5py python3-nose python3-lxml python3-matplotlib python3-numpy python3-protobuf python3-dateutil python3-skimage python3-scipy python3-six python3-networkx python3-tk libboost-python-dev  Clone NCSDK  cd ~ git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using RTL-SDR to Read Values From Wireless Electric/Gas/Water Meters</title>
      <link>https://debsahu.github.io/posts/using-rtl-sdr-to-read-values-from-wireless-electric-gas-water-meters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://debsahu.github.io/posts/using-rtl-sdr-to-read-values-from-wireless-electric-gas-water-meters/</guid>
      <description>    An attempt to use RTL-SDR to read values from wireless electric/gas/water meters and visualize these values on Home Assistant.
Software Based on bemasher/RTLAMR Project: https://github.com/bemasher/rtlamr
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
