<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IFTTT on Debashish Sahu</title>
    <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/tags/ifttt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IFTTT on Debashish Sahu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.debashishsahu.com/tags/ifttt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Talking to Twitter Using TwitterWebAPI for ESP8266</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/talking-to-twitter-using-twitterwebapi-for-esp8266/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/talking-to-twitter-using-twitterwebapi-for-esp8266/</guid>
      <description>Idea:  Use ESP8266 to talk to Twitter Get User Data or Tweet or Search Twitter Display the data on a Dot-Matrix display  Implementation I created an Arduino library to talk to Twitter using its Web API made for ESP8266. There are other approaches like using a bearer token arduino-twitter-api, but comes with limitations in terms of not being able to send tweet. This Arduino library TwitterWebAPI can both search/read and post tweets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Dot Matrix Display: Twitter Mentions Using ESP8266 Adafruit.io and IFTTT</title>
      <link>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/iot-dot-matrix-display-twitter-mentions-using-esp8266-adafruit-io-and-ifttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.debashishsahu.com/posts/iot-dot-matrix-display-twitter-mentions-using-esp8266-adafruit-io-and-ifttt/</guid>
      <description>Let’s say that you don’t have your smartphone around and someone mentions you on twitter. Wouldn’t it be nice to have a display that automatically reads your twitter mentions and show it on a scrolling display? So let’s build a internet controlled (IoT) dot-matrix display that does this for us using an ESP8266.
The plan to accomplish this is as follows:  Someone mentions us on twitter (in my case @debsahu) IF This Then That (IFTTT) tracks these mentions and posts this data on Adafruit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
